St. Peter State Hospital
Minnesota Historical Society
Daily reports and records.
1893-1964.
Minnesota Historical Society
St. Peter State Hospital.
Daily narratives and records documenting the medical condition of individual patients, including those kept by the assistant physician (1894-1900), head nurse (1893-1913), head nurse, detention hospital (1911-1913), and a general record (1912-1917, 1923-1927, 1963-1964).
7.7 cu. ft. (7 boxes, 3 partial boxes).
CATALOG HEADINGS
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the Minnesota Historical Society. Researchers desiring materials about related topics should search the catalog using these headings.
Topics:
Dangerously mentally ill -- Minnesota -- Medical care.; Medicine -- Minnesota.; Mentally ill -- Minnesota.; People with mental disabilities -- Institutional care -- Minnesota.; Psychiatric hospital patients -- Diseases -- Minnesota.; Psychiatric hospitals -- Minnesota -- Administration.; State hospitals -- Minnesota -- Administration.
Places:
Saint Peter (Minn.)
Document Types:
Medical records.
ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION
Access Restrictions:
A portion of these records contain private data. They are restricted for 50 years from date of commitment and are noted in the finding aid. Researchers may apply to use these records in accordance with the State Archives access statement.
Accession Information:
Accession number(s): 200; 2007-30
DETAILED DESCRIPTION
- Daily reports of assistant physician, 1894-1900.
  Chronologically arranged series of records for men and women for each year; document the conditions of patients ill or convalescent, patients well enough to go home, and any recommendations.
  - Men, February 9-December 28, 1894.
  - Women, February 6-December 31, 1894., 2 folders.
  - 1895-1900., 12 volumes.
    Separate volumes for men and women for each calendar year.
- Daily reports of head nurse, 1893-1913.
  Chronological daily narrative record that includes the names and medical conditions of patients who are ill; separate volumes for men and women.
  - Men’s Department.
    - 1893-1898., 6 volumes.
    - 1899-1900., 2 volumes.
    - 1902-July 31, 1907., 4 volumes.
    - August 1, 1907-August 31, 1910., 4 volumes; 1 folder.
    - March 1, 1911-January 6, 1913., 3 volumes.
  - Women’s Department.
    - 1893-1899., 6 volumes.
    - 1899-1900., 2 volumes.
    - 1902-1905., 3 volumes.
    - 1906-April 8, 1913., 6 volumes.
- Daily reports of head nurse, detention hospital, August 16, 1911-February 26, 1913., 3 folders.
  Chronological daily narrative record, that includes the names and medical conditions of patients (men and women) who were ill.
- Daily medical records books, 1912-1917, 1923-1927, 1963-1964.
  Chronological daily narrative record that includes the names and medical conditions of patients who are ill.
  - March 21, 1912–September 26, 1917., 1 volume.
  - July 15, 1923-February 11, 1927., 2 volumes.
  - November 12, 1963-April 10, 1964., 1 volume.
    RESTRICTED